<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Visit Irsina</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="ita">ITA</string>
    <string name="eng">ENG</string>
    <string name="fra">FRA</string>
    <string name="prova">Hello Word!</string>
    <string name="cambio">Changer la langue</string>
    <string name="seleziona">Select Language</string>
    <string name="storia">History and Description</string>
    <string name="orari">Timetable</string>
    <string name="vedere">What see</string>
    <string name="statua">Mantegna\'s statue</string>
    <string name="miglionico">Miglionico\'s paintings</string>
    <string name="cripta">Crypt</string>
    <string name="scegli">Choose a place on the map for more information</string>
    <string name="fuori_mappa">Fuori Mappa</string>
    <string name="continua">Continue</string>
    <string name="porticella">Porticella</string>
    <string name="porticellatesto">Irsina has always enchanted tourists with its narrow streets with unique landscapes, the Porticella offers a glimpse of unforgettable scenery.</string>
    <string name="muretto">Antiche Mura</string>
    <string name="murettotesto">The town, enclosed by mighty medieval fortifications, controls, from the top of a rugged hill marked by deep incisions, the valleys of Bradano and Basentello.</string>
    <string name="nuget">Palazzo Nugent</string>
    <string name="nugettesto">The Nugent palace was built on the former medieval castle dating back to the 14th-15th century. and incorporates Porta Maggiore, the main access point to the city. In the 18th century the feudatories of Montepeloso, the Riario Sforza, transformed the fortress into the family\'s residence.The structure, defended outside by a high wall curtain, develops around a quadrangular courtyard which is accessed from the finely worked portal. The well is decentralized to its usual position in the middle of the courtyard. On the court there are the three wings of the building that develops on two levels: the first there are rooms with barrel vaults for warehouses, the second the apartments of the feudal lord.</string>
    <string name="bottini">Bottini</string>
    <string name="bottinitesto">It consists of <b>underground tunnels</b> at human height.The thick layer of alluvial sediments and the overlying impermeable layers of clay have created a geomorphic situation that allows the accumulation of large quantities of water. The water captured from the subsoil, settles in tanks, and after being purified is channeled until the eighteenth-century outdoor fountain, from which flows fresh and pure from twelve mouths.</string>
    <string name="fontane">12 Fontane</string>
    <string name="fontanetesto">This eighteenth-century plant canalizes the very pure underground water and guarantees a refreshing break in the green landscape.</string>
    <string name="peschiera">Peschiera</string>
    <string name="peschieratesto">The fountains in this area were used both as drinking troughs and for washing clothes, the sanctuary was erected in the late sixteenth century, probably commissioned by Roman art lovers.</string>
    <string name="pieta">Chiesa della Pietà</string>
    <string name="juso">Madonna dello Juso</string>
    <string name="cancelle">Cancelle</string>
    <string name="testocancelle">Cancelle</string>
    <string name="cenni_storici_sanfra_titolo">Storia e Descrizione</string>
    <string name="cenni_storici_sanfra">The Franciscans, who arrived in Irsina in 1300, built the convent and the church in 1531, rebuilt in 1717. The Franciscan presence in Irsina is indicated in the first half of the 14th century. The construction of the conventual complex was begun in 1531, when the Franciscan order received a notable impulse from Pope Clement VII who dismissed the Benedictines and recognized the rights of Conventuals of Saint Francis to the friars. The Church, which presents a single nave with side chapels.</string>
    <string name="vedere_janora">What see</string>
    <string name="cripta_catt">Cripta</string>
    <string name="cripta_catt_testo">Testo Cripta</string>
    <string name="orari_museo">Timetable Museo</string>
    <string name="orari_francesco">Timetable Chiesa San Francesco</string>
    <string name="orari_cattedrale">Timetable Cattedrale</string>
    <string name="cenni_storici_catt">The origin is very ancient,according to experts, the cathedral was rebuilt after a fire by the Prince of Salerno Giovanni. in 1333 it was rebuilt again after a looting. Only the bell tower and the crypt have maintained their original appearance, the lower part is Romanesque, the upper Gothic, with mullioned windows and hanging arches. The cathedral has a front in Neapolitan Baroque forms, with a richly decorated central portal. The plant is formed by a Latin cross with three naves divided by pillars and ending with three apses.</string>
    <string name="miglionico1"><b>Irsina</b> preserves an enormous patrimony of eighteenth-century paintings attributed to the Campania artist Andrea Miglionico. His paintings are preserved in the Cathedral, in the Carmine church and in the church of Sant\'Agostino. In the eighteenth century Naples continues to remain the point of reference for all the art of Southern Italy. The paintings of the Neapolitan school come to this period in Basilicata and are inspired by the great master Luca Giordano. One of the best students of the Neapolitan master is surely <b><i>Andrea Miglionico</i></b>.</string>
    <string name="miglionico2">In Irsina are kept important paintings made between 1704 and 1706. <b>VISITATION</b> (oil on canvas of 139 × 190 cm) - <b>VIRGIN BETWEEN ST. JOHN THE BAPTIST, SANTA ROSA DA LIMA AND SAN LORENZO</b> (oil on canvas of 129 × 154 cm) - In the church of Sant'Agostino, once outside the walls of the historic center, is preserved the painting depicting <b>THE WEDDING OF CANA</b>.
</string>
    <string name="mantegna">"The statue of St. Eufemia, sculpted by Andrea Mantegna, is kept in the Cathedral of Irsina.It is a testimony of the artist's sculptural activity, St. Euphemia, the Great Martyr, born of a Christian family in Calcedonia,she died in 303 martyred because she won't to renounce her Christian faith during the last persecution of Emperor Diocletian.The imposing statue in the round, sculpted and painted around 1453 by Andrea Mantegna, 1.72 m tall, weight of q. 3.50 is in Nanto stone. The sculpture was placed in the 1700s in the chapel dedicated to her, next to the main altar, at the end of the right aisle. the statue was the protagonist in Mantua of the exhibition for the fifth centenary of the death of Andrea Mantegna, in 2006. The martyr is depicted as a classical statue, with a slightly advanced right leg, wrapped in a sage-green dress. The left hand holds the model of the city of Montepeloso, while the right hand is inserted into the jaws of the lion next to it. The face is slightly turned to the right and shows a mysterious smile, the lips are parted, giving the impression that the saint speaks. The back is sculpted with a care and a minuteness of extraordinary details. The hair falls softly on the shoulders with extreme lightness. The lion, proud and imposing in the front, is tame in the back, with the tail between the legs, as the most docile of pets.  "</string>
    <string name="cripta_sanfrancesco">The frescoes in the crypt of San Francesco are a clear reference to Giotto\'s painting. In the frescoes of the hypogeum chapel of San Francesco, obtained within a quadrangular tower of the Norman castle, the reference to Giotto\'s painting is clear not only in the architecture but also in the spirituality of the characters. Founded as a Franciscan oratory, in the fourteenth century it was chosen as a noble chapel by Del Balzo who had a fundamental role in Irsina in the promotion of important artistic enterprises including the concept of the pictorial cycle, wanted by Margherita and her daughter Antonia, portrayed among the characters depicted.The chapel, frescoed by artists close to Roberto d\'Oderisio, the most famous of the Neapolitan Giottesque painters, denotes multiple influences of the Florentine, Sienese, Pisan, Neapolitan and Roman schools. The frescoes, which are developed along the walls and on the vault of the chapel whose dimensions are m.7 and m.4, unknown until the early twentieth century. The representation recalls the Celtic-Irish miniatures in the gigantic, flattened face in the long white beard. The Creator is surrounded by multicolored concentric circles representing the universe and is supported by four angels. At the corners of the angels four lobed frames depict the symbols of the four evangelists.</string>
    <string name="pietatesto">The plant, like most small churches, is central and elongated. The first document that certifies the existence of the church is a perspective view contained in the text Kingdom of Naples in perspective of 1703 by G. B. Pacichelli. The earthquake of 1980 has aggravated the situation of deterioration causing lesions on the sides and on the facade, but a recent restoration has allowed the recovery of the structure.</string>
    <string name="jusotesto">The Church, called Santa Maria Nova, as opposed to the ancient Cathedral, Santa Maria Veteris, was built by the Basilian monks who settled in what was one of the most fertile areas of the country and still today is called the district of the gardens or \"Greeks\" became the seat of a priory, and constituted the most distant of Casadeian dependencies and the only one south of Lucca. The concentration of vast noble and ecclesiastical powers in the hands of the monks aroused constant friction with the clergy and the local lords. The negligence of the following centuries left almost no stone for the monastic buildings.</string>
    <string name="vedere_janora_testo">The Janora Civic Museum houses the precious collection of the historian and archaeologist Michele Janora, born in Montepeloso.Its passion for antiquity leads him to collect a large amount of archaeological artifacts and to keep them in the family palace.The collection was bought by the Municipality of Irsina in 1981 as a patrimony of the entire community.The most important nucleus of the collection consists of ceramic with geometric decoration, with red figures, black paint, acroma, weapons and ornaments in bronze and iron dating from prehistoric times to the Hellenistic age. A selection of about 300 artefacts specially studied and restored is exhibited in the entire collection.</string>
    <string name="testocancelle_acquistabile">Prodotti acquistabili:</string>
    <string name="crocifisso">Above the high altar, the wooden crucifix of the Donatello school (1454).</string>
    <string name="pulpito">The chorus and wooden pulpit, both of the 700\'s</string>
    <string name="statua_pizzolo">A stone statue od the Madonna with the child of Nicolò Pizzolo (half of the XV century)</string>
    <string name="fonte_battesimale">Baptisimal font in finely worked red marble</string>
    <string name="descrizione_catt">La cattedrale presenta una facciata in forme barocche napoletane, con un portale centrale riccamente decorato. La pianta a croce latina e tre navate suddivise da pilastri e terminanti con tre absidi, con transetto sormontato da una cupola, e con cappelle laterali creano lo spazio interno.</string>
    <string name="descrizione_catt_titolo">Description</string>
    <string name="cenni_storici_catt_titolo">History</string>
</resources>
